export const CHEMISTRYA2013 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. The atomic theory was put forward by",
A: "Avogadro.",
B: "Dalton.",
C: "Gay Lussac.",
D: "Rutherford.",
answer: "B. Dalton.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. A balanced equation is based on the law of",
A: "chemical equilibrium.",
B: "conservation of mass.",
C: "definite proportion.",
D: "multiple proportion.",
answer: "B. conservation of mass.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. The number of atoms in one mole of a substance is equal to the",
A: "atomic number.",
B: "Avogadro’s number.",
C: "mass number.",
D: "oxidation number.",
answer: "B. Avogadro's number.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. The noble gases are",
A: "diatomic.",
B: "monoatomic.",
C: "polyatomic.",
D: "triatomic.",
answer: "B. monatomic.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. An element has a valency of",
A: "1.",
B: "2.",
C: "3.",
D: "4.",
answer: "A. 1",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. The classification of elements in the periodic table is based on",
A: "mass number.",
B: "number of neutrons.",
C: "number of protons.",
D: "relative atomic mass.",
answer: "C. number of protons",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. Which of the following statements about the periodic table is/ are correct? \nI. Atomic radius increases across the period \nII. Electron affinity decreases down the group \nIII. Ionic character increases across the period \nIV. Ionization energy decreases down the group.",
A: "II and IV only",
B: "I and III only",
C: "II and III only",
D: "I only",
answer: "A. II and IV only",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. An element M forms a compound MCl5. In which group of the periodic table is M?",
A: "I",
B: "Ill",
C: "V",
D: "VII",
answer: "C. V",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Which of the following instruments could be used to detect the presence of isotopes?",
A: "Cathode ray tube",
B: "Electron microscope",
C: "Geiger Muller counter",
D: "Mass spectrometer",
answer: "D. Mass spectrometer",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. Which of the following noble gases has electron structure similar to that of N in NH3?",
A: "36Kr",
B: "18Ar",
C: "10Ne",
D: "2He",
answer: "C. 10Ne",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. Which of the following electron configurations is the most stable”",
A: "[Ar] 4s1 3d5",
B: "[Ar] 4s2 3d1",
C: "[Ar] 4s2 3d6",
D: "[Ar] 4s2 3d10",
answer: "D. [Ar]4s23d10",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. Which of the following statements about the 2s and 2p orbitals is correct?",
A: "Electrons in the 2p are more strongly attracted to the nucleus.",
B: "They have the same maximum number of electrons.",
C: "They have the same maximum number of sub-orbitals",
D: "The 2s has a lower energy than the 2p",
answer: "D. The 2s has a lower energy than the 2p",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. Covalent bonding results in the formation of",
A: "atoms.",
B: "ions.",
C: "molecules.",
D: "salts.",
answer: "C. molecules.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. The strength of metallic bonds depends on the",
A: "charge density of the atoms.",
B: "position of metals in the periodic table.",
C: "number of valence electrons.",
D: "total number of electrons in the atoms.",
answer: "C. number of valence electrons.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. A compound is formed when 3X combines with 8X. Determine the formula of the compound.",
A: "X8 Y3",
B: "X2Y",
C: "X3Y8",
D: "XY2",
answer: "B. X2Y",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. Determine the total number of shared pair electrons in the compound.",
A: "12",
B: "10",
C: "6",
D: "5",
answer: "C. 6",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Which of the following compounds has the strongest hydrogen bonding?",
A: "HF",
B: "H2S",
C: "H2Te",
D: "CH4",
answer: "A. HF",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. The polarizing power of a cation is enhanced by its",
A: "small nuclear charge and small size.",
B: "high nuclear charge and large size.",
C: "high ionization energy and low electron affinity.",
D: "high nuclear charge and small size.",
answer: "D. high nuclear charge and small size.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. A solution of NaOH with concentration 2.0 mol dm-3 is contained in 25 cm3 of its volume. Determine the amount of NaOH in the solution.",
A: "0.20 moles.",
B: "0.13 moles.",
C: "0.08 moles.",
D: "0.05 moles.",
answer: "D. 0.5 moles",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. Determine the volume of 0.10 mol dm-3 H2SO4 that could be used to neutralize 20.0 cm3 of 0.25 mol dm-3 KOH.",
A: "10.0 cm3.",
B: "12.5 cm3.",
C: "20.0 cm3.",
D: "25.0 cm3.",
answer: "D. 25.0 cm3",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. A volume of 100 cm3 Na2CO3 solution was prepared with concentration 0.30 mol dm-3. Determine the mass of Na2CO3 that was used for the preparation. [Na2CO3 = 106]",
A: "0.318 g",
B: "3.18 g",
C: "31.8 g",
D: "318 g",
answer: "B. 3.18 g",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Which of the following statements about matter is correct?",
A: "Kinetic energy of particles decreases from gas to solid",
B: "Orderliness of particles decreases from gas to solid",
C: "Random motion of particles decreases from solid to gas",
D: "There is increased compressibility in solid",
answer: "A. Kinetic energy of particles decreases from gas to liquid",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. The movement of particles from a region of higher concentration to a region of lower concentration is",
A: "Brownian motion.",
B: "dialysis.",
C: "diffusion.",
D: "osmosis.",
answer: "C. Diffusion.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. Which of the following gases has the least rate of diffusion under the same conditions? [H = 1.0; C = 12.0; O = 16.0; N = 14.0; S = 32.0]",
A: "NO2",
B: "CO2",
C: "SO2",
D: "H2S",
answer: "C. SO2",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. Fractional distillation is a technique generally used for the separation of",
A: "miscible liquids with close boiling points.",
B: "immiscible liquids.",
C: "two liquids with different densities.",
D: "two liquids with different molar masses.",
answer: "A. miscible liquids with close boiling points.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. Hess’s law states that the total enthalpy change for a reaction is",
A: "independent of the path taken.",
B: "dependent on the path taken.",
C: "changed when the conditions are changed.",
D: "always constant.",
answer: "A. independent of the path taken.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. The pH of waste water from a factory was found to be 3.2. Which of the following substances could be used to neutralize the water before it is released into the river?",
A: "Ammonium tetraoxosulphate (VI)",
B: "Lime",
C: "Sulphur (IV) oxide",
D: "Trioxonitrate (V) acid",
answer: "B. Lime",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. The salt, Mg(OH)NO3 is an example of a",
A: "normal salt.",
B: "double salt.",
C: "complex salt.",
D: "basic salt.",
answer: "D. Basic salt.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. Which of the following oxides is neutral to moist litmus paper?",
A: "H2O",
B: "CO2",
C: "SO3",
D: "NO2",
answer: "A. H2O",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Which of the following compounds has the lowest solubility in water at room temperature?",
A: "KClO3",
B: "KNO3",
C: "Ca(OH)2",
D: "NaCl",
answer: "A. KCIO3",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Which of the following statement about the solution HCl and CCl4 is correct? It",
A: "gives effervescence with Na2CO3",
B: "turns red litmus blue",
C: "does not conduct electricity",
D: "reacts with sodium to liberate hydrogen.",
answer: "C. does not conduct electricity",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. The rate equation of a reaction is R = K [X]2 [Y]. By what factor would the rate of reaction increase if the concentrations of X and Y are both doubled?",
A: "16",
B: "8",
C: "4",
D: "2",
answer: "B. 8",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Which of the following factors would increase the rate of reaction?",
A: "Increasing the volume of oxygen",
B: "Decreasing the temperature",
C: "Decrease the quantity of reactant",
D: "Addition of MnO2",
answer: "A. Increasing the volume of oxygen",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. Which of the following half-cell reaction equations correctly represents the electrolysis of a copper solution",
A: "Cu(s) + 2e_ → Cu2+(aq)",
B: "Cu(s) – e– → Cu+(aq)",
C: "Cu+(aq) + e– → Cu(s)",
D: "Cu2+(aq) + 2e– → Cu(s)",
answer: "D. Cu2++2e−➔Cu(s)",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. The following equation gives the half-cell reaction for the electrolysis of dilute H2SO4: 4OH– → 2H2O + O2 + 4e– The equation represents",
A: "dehydration.",
B: "hydration.",
C: "oxidation",
D: "reduction.",
answer: "C. oxidation.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. Electrical energy is produced by a simple cell as a result of",
A: "ionization of the electrolytes",
B: "formation of negative ions from atoms",
C: "transfer of electrons from reactive elements to a less reactive element",
D: "reaction of positive ions to negative ions",
answer: "C. transfer of electrons from reactive elements to a less reactive element.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. Consider the following electrochemical cell notation: Zn(s) / Zn2+(aq) // Cu2+(aq) / Cu(s). The negative electrode is",
A: "zinc metal.",
B: "zinc ions.",
C: "copper metal.",
D: "copper ions.",
answer: "A. zinc metal.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. Complete hydrogenation of benzene produces",
A: "cyclohexane.",
B: "cyclohexene.",
C: "magarine.",
D: "oil.",
answer: "A. cyclohexane.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. Which reaction is represented by the following equation? C2H2 + Br2 → C2H2Br2",
A: "Addition",
B: "Condensation",
C: "Polymerization",
D: "Substitution",
answer: "A. Addition",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. Which of the following statements about protein and carbohydrate is correct? They",
A: "are made by condensation polymerization.",
B: "contain same functional group.",
C: "hydrolyze to produce the same compounds.",
D: "are made from same monomer.",
answer: "A. are made by condensation polymerization",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. A compound with molecular formula CH2O2 is",
A: "a carbohydrate.",
B: "a carboxylic acid.",
C: "an ester.",
D: "an alkanol.",
answer: "B. a carboxylic acid.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. The reaction of an organic acid with an alkanol is known as",
A: "saponification.",
B: "neutralization.",
C: "hydrogenation.",
D: "esterification.",
answer: "D. esterification.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. The IUPAC name of C2H5COOC2H5 is",
A: "ethylethanoate.",
B: "ethylpropanoate.",
C: "propylethanoate.",
D: "propylpropanoate.",
answer: "B. ethylpropanoate.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. The final product obtained when cellulose is hydrolysed using a dilute mineral acid is",
A: "fructose.",
B: "glucose.",
C: "maltose.",
D: "sucrose.",
answer: "B. glucose.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. The products of fermentation of sugar (C6H12O6) are",
A: "ethanol and water.",
B: "ethanal and carbon (IV) oxide.",
C: "ethanal and enzymes.",
D: "carbon (IV) oxide and water.",
answer: "B. Ethanol and carbon (IV) oxide.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. The main impurity in haematite is",
A: "FeCO3",
B: "SiO2.",
C: "CaCO3",
D: "CaSiO3",
answer: "B. SiO2",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. Iron is better protected from corrosion by plating it with",
A: "copper.",
B: "tin.",
C: "silver.",
D: "zinc.",
answer: "D. Zinc.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. Which of the following metals is stored in paraffin oil?",
A: "Al",
B: "Fe",
C: "Mg",
D: "Na",
answer: "D. Na",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. Steel is obtained from iron by",
A: "alloying.",
B: "electroplating.",
C: "galvanizing.",
D: "roasting.",
answer: "A. alloying.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. Ammonia is manufactured industrially from its elements according to the equation represents",
A: "V2O5.",
B: "MnO2",
C: "Ni.",
D: "Fe.",
answer: "D. Fe",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},


]